Wisdom Ossai

No 4 Ogunaike Avenue Ojokoro Eyita, Ikorodu, Lagos 104001 Nigeria +2348067480053 - ossaiwisdom48@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Talented Software Engineer equipped with technical abilities and decisive nature necessary for successful job development. Expert in designing systems and optimising code. Focused and adaptable professional skilled at flexing to various positions to meet company and customer needs.

Skills

- HTML, CSS
- React
- Typescript
- Bootstrap and Tailwind and Material UI
- Debug software

- Javascript
- Angular
- Git
- Project coordination

Experience

01/2022 to Current Senior Software Engineer

Prunedge Development Technologies - Ogudu GRA, Lagos, Nigeria

- Collaborated with design team to create attractive and user-friendly websites.
- Reviewed proposed UI and UX designs for technical feasibility by collaborating with back-end development personnel.
- Created scalable, highly available and reliable software with Javascript, React, React Query, Material UI, and Redux.
- Implemented project initiation to ensure clean architecture for scalability and maintainability.
- Lead the frontend team through out the life span of each application development while handling feedback and assigning tasks to team members for bug fixes during the maintenance

phase.

10/2020 to 11/2021 Front End Engineer

Venture Garden Group - Ikeja , Lagos, Nigeria

- Collaborated with design team to create attractive and user-friendly web applications.
- Worked with the frontend team to create several Microfrontends with React and React App Rewired for managing various services officered by the Payment Gateway application.
- Contributed as a team member to the development of the OKR management solution.
- Collaborated with the Organisation's entire frontend team to build the its open source design system with React to achieve organisation-wide consistent user interface.

03/2019 to 09/2021 Front End Engineer

Xceed365 Limited - Marina, Lagos, Nigeria

- Participated in design sessions to get specifications for features to be added to the organisation's SaaS product.
- Collaborated with the API team to ensure release of the HCM solution features
- Lead a 3 man team consisting of one API and one Database to work on each feature assigned to us.
- Worked with technologies like Angular 6, Angular Material, Dev Express, Nx Workspace to achieve desired results.

05/2018 to 03/2019 Front End Developer Intern

Xceed365 Limited - Marina, Lagos, Nigeria

- Mastered Javascript and Learnt Angular to be properly equipped to actively participate in project contribution.
- Documented code changes in manuals to orient developers and users.
- Conducted automated user and integration tests to verify functionality.

Education

03/2014

Bachelor of Science: Industrial Mathematics

Delta State University - Abraka, Delta, Nigeria

- GPA 3.91.
- Graduated with honors.
- Member, National Association of Mathematics Students of Nigeria.
- Member, National Association of Science Students.

Languages

English, Fluent

hobbies

- Travelling
- Playing and watching soccer
- Hanging out with friends